Kyle Irvan





Career Summary

Creative, analytical instructional designer with eight years of experience developing eLearning and instructorled course offerings for global tier-one retailers, covering a range of store and enterprise retail technologies. Adept at a variety of eLearning development tools and learning management system administration. Documented success communicating effectively and working collaboratively with stakeholders at all

organizational levels.

Employment History

Senior Instructional Designer/Team Lead Toshiba Global Commerce Solutions – RTP, NC April 2016 - Present

- Produced dozens of quality courses for a variety of learner types with over 1000 combined completions
- Periodically review existing courses and update based on business and learner feedback
- Coordinate trainers, facilities, and shipping logistics for over 50 hands-on customer training workshops around the globe
- Prioritize, assign, and track and report status of projects of entire instructional design team
- Streamline learner experience through tailored learning paths and audience-specific curriculum development
- Work with business leadership to match learner objectives to business priorities
- Create course voiceovers with audio recording and editing tools
- Assess content resources, create storyboards, and set project timelines via needs analysis meetings with subject matter experts
- Manage multiple projects simultaneously with different teams
- Meet with internal teams to assess quality and coverage of existing education material

Leaning Specialist/Instructional Designer January 2013 – April 2016 Computer Task Group (CTG) – Morrisville, NC

Core Competencies/Skills

Instructional Design

- Lectora
- Articulate 360 Suite
- Camtasia

Webinar Facilitation

- Saba Meeting (Saba LMS)
- Adobe Connect

Learning Management System Administration

Saba Learning Management

Web Technologies

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript

General Technologies

- Microsoft Office 360
- Microsoft SharePoint
- Lotus Notes

Soft Skills

- Problem Solving Skills
- Clear Communication

Project Management

Managing projects for small education team

- Designed and built retail technology education courses on hardware and software configurations using Lectora and Articulate Storyline
- Held effective hands-on software workshops at domestic and international retail conferences

Assistant English Language Teacher August 2010 – July 2012 Kofu Board of Education – Tottori, Japan

Planned and taught English as a Foreign Language (EFL) lessons at an elementary school

Education